库珀探员.
Agent Cooper.
能听见我说话么? 我是安迪阿.
Can you hear me? It's Andy.
库珀探员, 我是安迪.
Agent Cooper, it's Andy.
能听到我说话么?
Can you hear me?
库珀探员?
Agent Cooper?
你好,客房服务.
Room service.
你躺在那下面干嘛呢?
How are you doing down there?
热奶来了.
Warm milk.
库珀探员?
Agent Cooper?
请你把它放在桌子上,可以么?
Would you put it on the table, please?
- 顺便帮我叫医生?
- 乐意效劳.
- And would you call a doctor?
- Sure.
你怎样了? 你能听见我么?
Are you aII right? Can you hear me?
库珀探员.
Agent Cooper.
库珀探员, 我是安迪阿.
你能听到我说话么?
Agent Cooper, it's Andy.
Can you hear me?
你那边出什么事了?
Are you aII right?
库珀探员. 库珀探员.
Agent Cooper. Agent Cooper.
库珀探员.
Agent Cooper.
我是安迪.
It's Andy.
我是安...--
It's An--
我帮你把电话挂了.
l hung it up for you.
什么?
What's that?
帮你把它挂了.
Hung it up for you.
那你叫医生了没?
Did you call the doctor?
医生?
The doctor?
挂了.
lt's hung up.
那个电话.
The phone.
谢谢.
Thank you.
是的.
Sure.
没问题.
No problem.
已经包括小费了吗?
Does this include a gratuity?
是的,先生.
Yes, sir.
谢谢,谢谢你这么大方.
Thank you. Thank you kindly.
牛奶要凉了.
The milk will get cool on you.
- 很快就凉了.
- 好的.
- Pretty soon.
- Okay.
我听说过你.
l've heard about you.
l heard about you.
我将给你3个暗示.
l will tell you three things.
如果它们都中了,
lf l tell them to you
and they come true,
到时候你会相信我吗?
then will you believe me?
你是谁?
Who's that?
把我当作你的朋友.
Think of me as a friend.
你从哪里来?
Where do you come from?
不要问我从哪里来,
应该问我将到哪里去?
The question is,
where have you gone?
这是我要给你的第一个暗示,
The first thing l will tell you is,
一个男人
there's a man
躺在一个微笑的袋子里.
in a smiling bag.
男人躺在一个微笑的袋子里.
Man in a smiling bag.
第二个暗示,
Second thing is,
不要给猫头鹰的外表迷惑了.
the owls are not what they seem.
第三个暗示,
Third thing is,
别给他用药, 他就会指引你.
without chemicals, he points.
你刚刚说的都是什么意思?
What do these things mean?
我只能暗示你这些.
This is all l am permitted to say.
把你的戒指给我.
Give me your ring.
当这些暗示都成真以后
我会还给你的.
l will return it to you
when you find these things to be true.
我们想帮助你.
We want to help you.
"我们"是谁?
Who's ''we''?
还有最后一件事.
One last thing.
里欧被锁在亨格力·豪斯里面.
Leo locked inside hungry horse.
线索就在里欧的亨格力·豪斯里面.
There's a clue at Leo's house.
你很快就会得到治疗.
You will require medical attention.
我敲, 我敲, 我敲敲.
Knock, knock, knock.
来呀.
Come on.
让我来看看你这新妞儿.
Let's have a look at the new girl.
噢,辣妹.
Vixen.
本杰明在哪间房?
What room is Ben in?
有小野花的那间.
The little flower room.
- 他为什么要瞒着我?
- 什么?
- Why is he holding out on me?
- What?
- 他为什么要瞒着我?
- 你说什么, 布莱奇?
- Why is he holding out on me?
- What's that, Blackie?
什么叫「瞒着你」?
Who's holding out on who?
求求你.
Please.
噢, 布莱奇.
Oh, Blackie.
你曾经是那么的漂亮.
You used to be so pretty.
布莱奇, 布莱奇.
Blackie, Blackie.
混蛋.
Bastard.
我想你可以走了.
l think you should go now.
- 真的, 想清楚了?
- 嗯, 是的. 想的很清楚了.
- Do you, Prudence?
- Yes, l do. l really do.
那好吧.
All right.
如果你坚持.
lf you insist.
逮到你了.
Gotcha.
我要生气了
l will huff
怒火呼呼的吹,
and puff,
把你的房顶吹翻.
and blow your house down.
噢, 宝贝, 宝贝.
Oh, my, my.
你这个宝贝
Aren't you something?
我今天非的要看看你不可，把你看给逼真.
l've got to see you. l must see you.
走开啦. 好羞人.
Go away. l'm shy.
难道没有人告诉你我是谁吗?
Didn't they tell you who l was?
大老板?
The owner?
完全正确.
That's right.
本, 我是哲.
出了点状况.
Ben, it's Jer.
We got a situation.
- 我这里也出了点状况.
- 本哥, 别玩了，我们要去「干活」了.
- So have l.
- Brother Ben, we got a S-N-A-G.
- 阿莱丝, 我这会儿真的要走囉.
- 快点, 本.
- Alas, l do have a situation.
- Come on, Ben.
来了, 哲.
Coming, Jer.
我喜欢你.
l like you.
你知道怎样钩引男人.
这样很重要.
You know how to interest a man.
That's half the battle.
下次见,
下次我们来玩点别的.
Next time,
we will play a different game.
我来订游戏规则.
l'll make the rules.
你会喜欢的. 很好玩的.
You'll like it. Fun game.
我们都会是赢家.
Everybody wins.
戴安.
Diane.
我的录音机在桌子上.
My recorder is on the table.
现在我够不着它.
l'm unable to reach it at this time.
只能希望
我无意中按过那个
l can only hope
that l inadvertently pressed
声控键.
the voice activation button.
我现在躺在房间的地板上.
l'm lying on the floor of my room.
我中枪了.
l've been shot.
剧痛
还留了一大滩血.
There's a great deal of pain
and a fair amount of blood.
幸好, 从昨晚开始我一直穿着防弹背心,
Fortunately, l was wearing
my bulletproof vest last night,
局里的规定
执行任务时必须要穿.
per bureau regulations
when working undercover.
我记得我把背心拉起来了一点,
l remember folding the vest up,
想抓一只木蚤.
trying to chase down a wood tick.
你能想象吗？
lf you can imagine the impact
on your chest
就像三个保龄球从九米高的地方砸下来一样,
of three bowling balls dropped
from a height of about 9 feet,
你可能已经开始在想象了吧.
you might begin
to approximate the sensation.
仔细想想,
All things considered,
其实中枪
并不像我一直想象中那么糟糕.
being shot is not as bad
as l always thought it might be.
只要你能保持住冷静，
不要恐惧.
As long as you can keep
the fear from your mind.
但我猜你可能笑我
「火星人都知道」.
But l guess you could say that
about almost anything in life.
真不像我想象中那么糟
只要你能保持住冷静，不要恐惧.
lt's not so bad as long as you can keep
the fear from your mind.
噢, 天啊.
Oh, my God.
我的戒指不见了.
The ring is gone.
在这种时候不见了, 太奇怪了,
At a time like this, curiously,
我开始
为自己感到很遗憾
you begin to think
of the things you regret
遗憾那些我错过的事.
or the things you might miss.
我很想...总之, 我希望在有生之年
能尽量多关心他人，并以礼相待.
l would like, in general, to treat people
with much more care and respect.
我还想去登山，登很高的山.
l would like to climb a tall hill.
也别太高.
Not too tall.
想坐在凉凉的绿草地上.
Sit in the cool grass.
也别太凉
Not too cool.
一边感受洒在脸上的温暖阳光.
And feel the sun on my face.
我还希望可以破了
灵博格的那个绑票案.
l wish l could have cracked
the Lindbergh kidnapping case.
我真的希望
和一个美人儿做爱
l would very much like
to make love to a beautiful woman
一个我真心爱的美人儿.
who l had genuine affection for.
啊还有, 还用说么?
我还要去西藏.
And of course, it goes without saying
that l would like to visit Tibet.
我盼望着西藏人民能重获他们的家园
达赖喇嘛也能重回家乡.
l wish they could get their country back
and the Dalai Lama could return.
噢, 太多东西想做了.
Oh, l would like that very much.
总而言之,
这次是个很有意思的体验.
All in all,
a very interesting experience.
他们终于来了.
They're here.
我的皮肤好痒.
My skin was itching.
当时有一只木跳蚤在爬.
Wood tick was crawling.
于是我就提起防弹背心.
l lifted my bulletproof vest.
三下重击.
Three slugs.
近距离开枪.
Point-blank range.
你看这个.
That explains this.
倒霉的木跳蚤，给打得稀巴烂.
Hell of a way to kill a tick.
你看到那个持枪歹徒的脸了吗?
Did you get a look at the gunman?
只看到了面具, 和枪口的火光.
l saw a masked face, muzzle flash.
露西, 你最好给库珀探员
汇报一下今天的情况.
Lucy, you better bring Agent Cooper
up-to-date.
里欧·强生中枪了.
Leo Johnson was shot.
雅克·雷诺被勒死了.
Jacques Renault was strangled.
锯木厂被烧燬了.
雪莉和皮特给浓烟熏倒了.
The mill burned.
Shelly and Pete got smoke inhalation.
凯萨琳和乔西都失了踪.
Catherine and Josie are missing.
纳丁服食过量安眠药
现在昏迷中.
Nadine is in a coma
from taking sleeping pills.
- 已经几点了?
- 早晨7:45了.
- How long have l been out?
- lt's 7:45 in the morning.
整晚
暂时都没什么动静
We haven't had this much action
in one night
只有59区的角鹿社俱乐部失火了.
since the Elk's Club fire of '59.
哈里, 我们要申请搜查令
去搜查里欧·强生的房子.
Harry, we need to get a search warrant
for Leo Johnson's house.
不用了. 里欧就在
自己的客厅中枪的.
No need. Leo was shot
in his own living room.
是戴佩提·布伦南发现他的.
Deputy Brennan found him.
- 你那儿都不能去.
- 医生. 当正义在召唤的时候,
- You're not going anywhere.
- Doc. When the will is invoked,
身体的复原能力
会变得非常惊人.
the recuperative powers of the physical
body are simply extraordinary.
只需要给我几个小时
换衣服.
Just give me a couple of hours
to get dressed.
我现在正站在
一大片的贮木场前
I'm standing just in front of
where a massive Iog-storage area
帕卡德锯木厂
被大火烧成一片废墟,
of the Packard Saw MiII
burned to the ground,
消防局的调查员
在彻底调查后声称这次是一个
under what fire department
investigators are caIIing
"神秘事件. "
''mysterious circumstances. ''
迄今为止, 这是我们能从官方
所获得的最多消息,
Now, poIice officiaIs have toId me
that they have, as of yet,
- 波比.
- 所获证据表明
- Bobby.
- uncovered no apparent Iink
这两个事件之间
似乎没有直接的关系
between these two
seemingIy unreIated
- 波比.
- 很可能只是两个不幸的意外.
- Bobby.
- tragedies.
这里是帕卡德锯木厂
现场为你直播...
Reporting Iive
from the Packard Saw MiII...
库珀, 你不能这样走
完全不顾自己的身体.
Cooper, this is totally
against my recommendations.
没事, 医生. 我会小心的.
lt's all right, doc. Duly noted.
你断了两条肋骨,
好些小软骨还没修复.
You got two busted ribs,
your cartilage is a mess.
天知道还会发生什么事故?
Who knows what else is wrong?
那是谁?
What's that?
雅克·雷诺.
Jacques Renault.
你觉得那个袋子在微笑吗?
ls that bag smiling?
微笑?
Smiling?
都这时候了,还有什么好微笑的?
What's there to smile about?
你想念贝丝吗?
Do you miss Beth?
啊?
What?
你想念你妈妈吗?
Have you been missing your mom?
- 莎拉姨妈?
- 嗯?
- Aunt Sarah?
- Yeah?
我昨天晚上作了个怪梦.
l had the strangest dream last night.
什么怪梦?
About what?
梦见了地毯.
The rug.
就在这里.
Right here.
从这里
我正坐着这里.
Right from this angle
where l'm sitting.
你梦见到劳拉了?
Was Laura in it?
噢,梅尔斯·杜丝和豆斯·杜丝
还有小绵羊戴维
Oh, Mairzy Doats and Dozy Doats
And IiddIe Iamzy divey
和小小戴维, 不是吗?
A kiddIey divey too, wouIdn't you?
噢,梅尔斯·杜丝和豆斯·杜丝
还有小绵羊戴维
Oh, Mairzy Doats and Dozy Doats
And IiddIe Iamzy divey
和小小戴维, 不是吗?
A kiddIey divey too, wouIdn't you?
现在, 来唱首怪歌
一定很好玩
Now, if the words sound queer
And funny to your ear
一起扭扭屁股乱唱歌
A IittIe bit jumbIed and jivey
唱, 「梅尔斯吃燕麦粥」
她最爱吃燕麦粥
Say, ''Mares eat oats
And does eat oats
「小绵羊却爱吃常春藤」
And IittIe Iambs eat ivy''
利兰?
Leland?
噢,梅尔斯·杜丝和豆斯·杜丝
还有小绵羊戴维
Oh, Mairzy Doats and Dozy Doats
And IiddIe Iamzy divey
和小小戴维, 不是吗?
A kiddIey divey too, wouIdn't you?
还有小小戴维, 不是吗?
早啊, 亲爱的.
Morning, dears.
噢,梅尔斯·杜丝和豆斯·杜丝
还有小绵羊戴维
Oh, Mairzy Doats and Dozy Doats
And IiddIe Iamzy divey
噢, 利兰.
Oh, Leland.
利兰姨父的头发都变白了.
Uncle Leland's hair turned white.
利兰, 回来.
Leland, come back here.
噢, 天啊.
Oh, God.
来. 日程表.
Okay. Agenda.
第一.
One.
我要知道凯萨琳现在是死是活.
l want a location on Catherine.
我们装作什么都不知道,
她来做替罪羊.
Keep our distance, just make sure
she's ready to take the fall.
第二.
Two.
我要知道
里欧·强生的详细病情
l want a complete medical
on Leo Johnson
看他到底有没康复的迹象
and his prospects for recovery
我还要汉克·詹宁斯
好好给我解释
and a satisfactory explanation
from Hank Jennings
为什么在格斯伍纪念公园的时候
里欧没有被警察捉去做酒精测验呢
why Leo isn't being measured
for a plot in Ghostwood Memorial Park.
不管怎样，有好开始就已经成功一半了.
Well begun is half done.
噢,梅尔斯·杜丝和豆斯·杜丝
还有小绵羊戴维
Oh, Mairzy Doats and Dozy Doats
And IiddIe Iamzy divey
还有小小戴维, 不是吗?
A kiddIey divey too, wouIdn't you?
噢,梅尔斯·杜丝和豆斯·杜丝
还有小绵羊戴维
Oh, Mairzy Doats and Dozy Doats
And IiddIe Iamzy divey
还有小小戴维, 不是吗?
A kiddIey divey too, wouIdn't you?
现在, 来唱首怪歌
一定很好玩
Now, if the words sound queer
And funny to your ear
一起扭扭屁股乱唱歌
A IittIe bit jumbIed and jivey
唱, 「梅尔斯吃燕麦粥」
她最爱吃燕麦粥
Say, ''Mares eat oats
And does eat oats
「小绵羊却爱吃常春藤」
And IittIe Iambs eat ivy''
我回来了.
l'm back.
整装待发.
Back and ready.
但是子弹是从外面射进来的.
But the bullet came from outside.
你有什么意见?
How do you figure?
警长, 这不是已经很清楚了吗.
Sheriff, a picture is forming.
一把大斧头在沙发上.
Big ax on the couch.
案发当晚
这些鹅如常飞着.
These same geese were flying
that evening.
里欧当时正
猛推着某个人.
Leo was trying to turn someone
into kindling.
那个人撞到了电视机, 把它撞歪了.
That person hit the TV, moved it.
你看到这个印了没有
地毯上的这个.
You can see the depression
in the carpet.
雪莉?
Shelly?
雪莉·强生约99磅重
而且浑身都湿透了.
Shelly Johnson's about 99 pounds
soaking wet.
这是一台大电视.
This is a big TV.
里欧冲上前, 举起斧头.
Leo advanced, ax raised.
然后呢?
Then what happened?
子弹穿过窗户,
把里欧放到在沙发上.
Bullet came through the window,
knocked Leo back onto the couch.
你觉得是雪莉开的枪吗?
不是她的话，又是谁开的枪呢?
Do you think it was Shelly
who pulled the trigger?
警长, 可以先暂时,
忽略雪莉吗.
Sheriff, get your mind off Shelly,
for a moment.
我们不会知道雪莉做过什么
直到我们查出她当晚到底是几点到锯木厂的.
We won't know about Shelly until we
find out what time she got to the mill.
有惊喜给大伙儿. 肉欲世界.
Surprise. FIesh WorId.
嘿, 第几期?
Hey, what issue is this?
还是没找到可卡因.
卡车上和这里都没有.
Still no cocaine.
Here or in the truck.
但我在车上找到这个.
But l found this in the truck.
里欧的抹布.
Leo's duster.
- 汽油味很重.
- 锯木厂.
- Reeks of gasoline.
- The mill.
干得好, 豪克.
Good work, Hawk.
哈里, 你看谁来了?
Harry, do you know who it is?
- 哈里.
- 外面再喊什么?
- Harry.
- What's that?
- 哈里, 你看谁来了?
- 是安迪再喊.
- Harry, do you know who it is?
- lt's Andy.
他看起来
好像很不高兴.
He seems pretty upset
about something.
哈里, 是罗森菲尔德探员.
Harry, it's Agent Rosenflower.
安迪, 你没事吧?
Andy, are you all right?
嘿, 安迪.
Hey, Andy.
你怎样啦?
Are you all right?
又一个执法史上
值得纪念的时刻.
And it's another great moment
in law enforcement history.
嘿, 艾伯特.
Hey, Albert.
你的到来似乎还是
有那么一点贡献的.
Looks like you were more right
than you know.
一双新靴子
还有一大包可卡因.
Looks like a new pair of boots
and a lot of cocaine.
安迪.
Andy.
干得好.
Good work.
馅饼太赞了!
Hot damn that pie is good!
这是劳拉的眼镜
你想要的那副.
Here's Laura's glasses
that you wanted.
谢谢.
Thanks.
唐娜, 你看这副眼镜
我正带着的?
Donna, do you see these glasses
that l'm wearing?
嗯.
Yeah.
我讨厌它.
l hate them.
我再也不会带了.
l'm never wearing these again.
好的.
Okay.
詹姆斯真的给抓起来了?
ls it true about James?
他昨晚整晚都呆在监狱里.
He spent the night in jail.
你觉得
是我们害他给抓的吗?
Do you think
it's because of what we did?
你看, 如果我们什么都不做
就什么都不会知道了.
Look, we don't know
if we did anything.
我爸说杰柯比是给人袭击
才送进医院的.
My dad said Jacoby got sick
because he was attacked.
我们只是给他寄了一盒录像带而已.
All we did was send him a tape.
但是，如果不是我们骗他出来
他可能也不会受伤.
Maybe he wouldn't have been attacked
if we hadn't.
可能. 你怎么不想想可能你今天不洗头
明天太阳还升不起来呢.
Maybe. Maybe the sun won't come
up tomorrow if you wash your hair.
别老是有这些让人抓狂的念头
干了就干了，没什么好后悔的.
Think like that and you're gonna
go crazy. What's done is done.
现在唯一能让我们
摆脱困境的办法
The only way this won't come back
to haunt us
就是什么都别说
尤其是那天晚上的事.
is if we keep quiet
about what happened last night.
我敢向你保证
詹姆斯也会这样做的.
l can assure you
James is doing the same thing.
明白了吗?
Get the picture?
一清二楚.
Loud and clear.
利兰姨父的头发一夜之间全白了.
Uncle Leland's hair turned white.
真的?
Really?
白的像鬼一样.
White as a sheet.
太怪异了.
Weird.
唐娜, 有你的信.
Donna, l have something for you.
昨天
邮寄来「双食餐厅」这里的.
Came here to the Double R
yesterday.
谢谢, 诺玛.
Thanks, Norma.
- 天啊.
- 怎么了?
- God.
- What is it?
"借上门送餐服务的机会去调查."
''Look into the Meals on Wheels.''
我怎样才能尽量讲的简单点呢, 库珀?
How simple can l make it, Cooper?
联邦探员查案，
联邦探员中枪.
FBl agent gets shot,
FBl agent investigates.
而我刚好就在附近, 我西雅图的实验室里,
之前又插手过这件案子.
l'm in proximity, work in the Seattle lab,
l'm familiar with the underlying case.
- 疼吗?
- 嗯.
- Does that hurt?
- Yes.
艾伯特, 重点是, 你在这里
是绝对不受当地人欢迎的.
Albert, the point is, you're not gonna
win any local popularity contests.
不, 重点是
我们的头，戈登·库尔派我回来的.
No, the point is
Gordon Cole ordered me back here.
吸气.
Breathe.
再来.
Again.
好.
Okay.
开枪打你的人是个右撇子
约5尺6寸到 5尺10寸高,
You were shot by a right-handed
person, 5'6'' to 5'1 0'' tall,
在3英尺范围内对你开枪.
今天下午我会去测量弹道.
at a distance of less than 3 feet.
l'll have ballistics this afternoon.
- 还有什么疑问吗?
- 嗯.
- You're still blank on the other details?
- Yes.
你当时干嘛
把背心那样子卷起来?
What was your vest doing
riding up like that?
木跳蚤.
Wood tick.
同时, 你的一号疑犯
被勒死在病床上,
Meanwhile, one of your principal
suspects is killed in his hospital bed,
另一个则差点在客厅里被枪杀.
the other is shot in his living room.
执行私刑?
还是在充梁山好汉?
Vigilante justice
or just clean country living?
艾伯特, 真搞不懂你这孬态度
到底从哪儿学回来的?
Albert, where does this attitude of
general unpleasantness come from?
我一定要回答你吗.
l'll have to get back to you on that.
如果你不想定期
变熊猫眼,
lf you don't want two black eyes
on a regular basis,
我劝你平心静气
过好这期田园生活.
l suggest you make
some kind of peace with rural life.
好极了. 跳完土风舞,
再来一程灰头土脸的肥料车旅行，不是吗.
Great. After the square dance,
maybe we can all take a hayride.
进来.
Come in.
安迪, 鼻子的伤好点了吗?
Andy, how's the nose?
还好没留疤痕,
只是喷了一鼻子血.
Not a mark on it,
only blood squirted out.
他的狗碗放哪了? 赶快拿来接血.
Where do they keep his water dish?
艾伯特.
Albert.
库珀探员, 猜猜看.
Agent Cooper, guess what.
你今天上午给我的谜语
我已经解开了.
l have the answer to the riddle
that you told me this morning.
我打电话去亨格力·豪斯监狱, 蒙大拿州.
l called Hungry Horse, Montana.
关键词是"锁".
The word ''locked.''
里欧·强生曾经在
蒙大拿州的亨格力·豪斯监狱被关押过.
Leo Johnson was locked in a jail
in Hungry Horse, Montana.
几时, 安迪?
When, Andy?
"1988年2月9日."
''February 9, 1 988.''
特里萨·班克斯.
Teresa Banks.
那看来特里萨·班克斯被谋杀的那晚
里欧·强生有不在场证据.
Looks like Leo has an alibi for the night
Teresa Banks was murdered.
做得好, 安迪.
Good work, Andy.
呵呵.
Yeah.
打扰一下.
Excuse me.
- 请问杜鲁门警长在么?
- 他在, 但是他现在正忙着呢.
- ls Sheriff Truman here?
- He is, but he is busy at the moment.
有什么可以帮助你吗?
May l help you?
我之前没有预约.
l'm afraid l don't have an appointment.
警长只是叫我
The sheriff asked me to stop by
有空的来走走.
at my convenience.
今天刚好路过.
This is the first convenient moment.
那有什么事吗?
May l ask what this is regarding?
我来向他推销鞋.
l'm here to sell him some shoes.
鞋?
Shoes?
妈妈来送
牛奶和曲奇了.
Here comes Mom
with miIk and cookies.
再说吧, 劳伦斯.
Later, Lawrence.
再见.
Bye-bye.
你是从杰柯比医生那里
拿到这盒录音带的?
You got this tape
from Dr. Jacoby's office?
是的.
Yeah.
你这是强行入侵他人住宅, 知道吗，詹姆斯.
That's breaking and entering, James.
当时门是开着的.
The door was open.
那你怎么知道
杰柯比不在屋里?
How did you know
Jacoby wouldn't be there?
我敲门了, 没人在.
l knocked, nobody answered.
- 你一个人?
- 是.
- You were alone?
- Yeah.
好吧. 我知道了
你只是想帮忙,
Okay. l know
you were trying to help,
但是别人
不这样认为.
but there's some people
who might not see it that way.
尤其是你的油箱里
藏着3盎司可卡因.
Especially with 3 ounces of cocaine
in your gas tank.
你知道不是我藏的.
You know l didn't put that there.
我想还有可能使
麦克和波比.
l think it was probably
Mike and Bobby.
- 是的.
- 哈里,
- Yeah.
- Harry,
劳拉在录音带里
提到了一个神秘人.
Laura talks on her tape
about a mystery man.
一辆红色跑车. 里欧·强生.
A red Corvette. Leo Johnson.
我想有可能是另外一个人.
不是雅克·雷诺.
l think it was somebody else.
Not Jacques Renault either.
- 为什么这样说?
- 我之前一直没有联想到
- Why do you say that?
- l never put it together
直到我听到她在录音带里说,
"这个人点燃了我的生命之火."
until l heard the tape. Where she says,
''This guy can really light my fire.''
好, 我还记得一个晚上
我们又开始见面了.
Well, l remember this one night when
we first started seeing each other.
她磕了药.
She was still doing drugs then.
然后, 我们到了树林里
她开始在那里胡念一些恐怖的诗,
Well, we were in the woods and
she started saying this scary poem,
一次又一次的, 提到火.
over and over, about fire.
然后她说,
And then she said,
"你要和我一起玩火吗,
小男生?"
''Would you like to play with fire,
little boy?''
"你要和鲍勃一起玩吗?"
''Would you like to play with Bob?''
- 那是什么意思?
- 我不知道.
- What did she mean by that?
- l don't know.
劳拉那晚说了好多胡话.
Laura said a lot of nutty stuff.
很多时候,
线索就是这样从你身边溜走了.
Half the time,
it just went right by you.
就这样, 动不了了.
This stuck, though.
詹姆斯, 我就直说了.
James, l'll get right to the point.
我知道劳拉·帕尔默的另一半项链
在你那里.
l know you have the other half
of Laura Palmer's necklace.
我要. 你把它交出来吧.
l want it. Give it to me.
怎么回事?
How?
好, 这是在杰柯比那里找到的.
Well, this was in Jacoby's office.
藏在一个空椰壳里.
lt was in a coconut.
椰壳?
A coconut?
豪克, 先把詹姆斯送回牢房里.
Hawk, take James back to his cell.
杰柯比?
Jacoby?
你怎么知道
项链在他那里?
How did you know
he had the necklace?
劳拉和詹姆斯曾经是一对的.
Laura and James were in love.
我就推测另一半项链
或许就在他那里,
l figured he had to have
the other half of the necklace,
但是如果他怀有那一半,
but if he had the other half,
他为什么不给我们
帮助破案呢.
he would have given it to us
to help with the case.
忽然，我茅塞顿开.
Then it dawned on me.
肯定有些什么人或事
在威胁着他.
Something or someone
frightened him off.
所以他不能交出来,
于是我就问他拿了.
He had to have it,
so l asked him for it.
杰柯比?
Jacoby?
我从来没料到
他和这个案子有什么关系.
l didn't figure he had anything
to do with this at all.
有些时候真得靠碰碰运气.
Sometimes you just get lucky.
唐娜?
Donna?
嗨, 露西.
Hi, Lucy.
我来看詹姆斯.
l'm here to see James.
你好吗?
How are you doing?
你告诉他们什么了?
Did you tell them anything?
他们还没问我呢.
They haven't asked me anything.
你什么时候开始抽起烟了?
When did you start smoking?
我偶尔就抽抽.
l smoke every once in a while.
有助于缓解紧张.
Helps relieve tension.
你什么时候开始变紧张了?
When did you get so tense?
我开始抽烟的时候.
When l started smoking.
你告诉他们什么了吗?
Did you tell them anything?
我没说你
和马迪的事.
l didn't tell them
about you or Maddy.
他们认为是里欧杀了劳拉?
Do they think Leo killed Laura?
我不知道他们怎么想.
l don't know what they think.
马迪呢?
How is Maddy?
她没事吧.
She's fine.
她也什么都没说.
She hasn't said anything either.
你想吻我吗?
So don't you wanna kiss me?
你怎么了?
What's wrong?
没怎么.
Nothing's wrong.
就想要你
不行吗?
Or is it just not okay
for me to want you?
快点出来, 詹姆斯.
Get out soon, James.
露西.
Lucy.
安迪.
Andy.
盒子里面的
是每一期的 肉欲世界
ln these boxes
is every edition of FIesh WorId
过往3年的出版都在这儿了.
published for the past three years.
这是特里萨·班克斯的照片,
第一个受害者,
This is a picture of Teresa Banks,
the first victim,
一年前在南部地区
遇害了.
who was found murdered a year ago
in the southern part of the state.
现在，劳拉和朗尼特的照片
出现过在杂志的一个广告栏里.
Now, Laura and Ronette's photographs
appeared in ads in the magazines.
你想我们找出
特里萨·班克斯的照片.
You want us to look for a picture
of Teresa Banks.
安迪, 你脑袋转的真快.
Andy, you're way ahead of me.
露西, 我和杜鲁门警长
去医院.
Lucy, Sheriff Truman and l
will be at the hospital.
你们好好表现吧.
Behave yourselves.
黛安, 刚刚收到
肉欲世界.的杂志 做得好.
Diane, just received the back issues
of FIesh WorId. Good work.
杂志社依法合作
真让我高兴,
lt's nice to see some cooperation
with the law,
特别是一家以
猎食人性弱点为生的公司.
especially from a company
that preys on human weaknesses.
露西, 和你一起看这些
我真是好别扭，太不好意思了.
Lucy, l sure feel uncomfortable
being in this situation with you.
什么不好意思? 给点专业精神好不好.
Why? We're both professionals.
还需要给他开点药吗?
ls he on something?
只有你能决定.
Only what you prescribed.
我认为至少
他吃了一点点东西.
l think he did take
a little bit of his food.
我的天啊, 可能吗?
My God, could that be it?
库珀探员.
Agent Cooper.
你好好跟心理医生说说
Why don't you tell the psychiatrist
你断了2条肋骨
还有那些裂了的小软骨.
about your broken ribs
and torn cartilage.
好, 好, 好.
Well, well, well.
告诉我你发生什么事了?
What happened to you?
少跟我来那些胡扯, 骗人的小把戏
或者来那些故作高深的心理学术语.
l don't want any baloney, magic tricks
or psychological mumbo jumbo.
我只是要你告诉我
你怎么会有这个的?
l want you to tell us
how you came into possession of this
还是你要我以妨碍司法公正罪
让你蹲大牢.
or l am gonna have to place you
under arrest for obstruction of justice.
别, 我告诉你.
Look, l told you.
劳拉死后的第二晚,
我跟踪了一辆红色跑车.
The night after Laura died,
l followed a man in a red Corvette.
里欧·强生.
Leo Johnson.
对.
Correct.
然后，他在锯木厂附近
把我给甩了.
Then he eluded me somewhere
near the old sawmill road.
当时我坐在那里, 正诅咒自己--
As l sat there, cursing my--
毕竟老了,
My lack of horsepower,
一辆摩托车开了过来.
a motorcycle drove by.
后面还跟着一辆警察巡逻车.
Followed by a police cruiser.
但你跟丢了.
But you lost them.
他们跑进树林里.
They went into the woods.
我看到他们了.
我跟着他们.
l saw them.
l followed them in there on foot.
- 詹姆斯和唐娜?
- 是的, 他们...
- James and Donna?
- Yes, they...
他们耳语了一阵,
但我没听清楚他们在说些什么.
They spoke intently for a while, but
l couldn't hear what they were saying.
我记得...
I remember it was...
那晚树林里很冷.
It was a coId night in the woods.
最后, 他们...
FinaIIy, they...
他们在地里埋了一些东西,
然后用一块石头压着.
They buried something in the ground,
under a rock.
或许没经大脑,
lll-advisedly, perhaps,
我就把它拿回来了，作为纪念品.
l took it as a keepsake.
是她的, 你懂么.
lt was her, you see.
项链.
The necklace.
一颗被割裂的心 .
A divided heart.
劳拉她--
Laura was--
她, 其实...
Was, in fact...
唉, 她过着一种双重生活.
Well, she was living a double life.
2个劳拉.
Two people.
是的, 但...
Yeah, but then...
我最后一次
见她, 她...
Then when l saw her
that last time, she...
我不知道, 她似乎
找回了一点--
l don't know, she seemed
to have reached a kind of--
宁静和自我.
A peace with herself.
现在我明白了
Now l believe that
是因为她终于
what she had in fact arrived at
决定给自己的生命画上句号了.
was a decision to end her life.
你说劳拉想了结了自己?
Are you saying Laura wanted to die?
医生,
Doctor,
劳拉·帕尔默
不是自杀的.
Laura Palmer
did not commit suicide.
不, 不.
No, no.
但或许是她允许自己
别杀害.
But maybe she allowed herself
to be killed.
还有一件事.
One more thing.
昨晚雅克·雷诺被杀害的时候
你就在旁边的特别护理病房.
You were in intensive care last night
when Jacques Renault was killed.
嗯, 是的.
但是, 不是吧, 各位.
Yeah, yes.
But l mean, come on, fellows.
我当时打了镇静剂...
l was heavily sedated and...
你看到什么了吗? 或听到什么?
Did you see anything? Hear anything?
我记得我听到
火警响了, 但...
l remember hearing
a fire alarm go off, but...
好像...
lt's...
就好像...
lt's all like a...
做了一个梦似的.
Like a dream.
我记还有一股气味.
There was a smell.
对, 有一股特别的气味.
Yeah, there was a peculiar smell.
是不是以防被害人挣扎的
麻醉剂的气味.
lt's usual in case of strangulation
for the victim to void his bowels.
不.
No.
不, 不是那种, 是...
No, that wasn't it, this...
闻起来就像...
This was a smell like...
像油.
Like oil.
烧焦了的机器润滑油.
Scorched engine oil.
布拉德利医生, 请到前台.
Dr. BradIey, caII the operator.
布拉德利医生,
请马上到前台.
Dr. BradIey,
caII the operator, pIease.
嘿, 睡美人.
Hey, sleeping beauty.
波比.
Bobby.
你来这里做什么?
如果让别人看见了怎么办?
What are you doing here?
What if someone sees you?
我不在乎.
我再也不在乎了.
l don't care.
l do not care anymore.
里欧也在医院呢.
Leo's in the hospital.
他中枪了.
Somebody shot him.
是, 我知道. 我是说, 我听说了.
有警员守在他房门口.
Yeah, l know. l mean, l heard
there's cops outside his room.
- 真得?
- 我还听说他们准备对付他.
- Really?
- l hear they're gonna bust him.
他这次肯定要给
逮个正着了, 可怜蛋.
He must have got caught
doing something, poor bastard.
你到底怎么了?
What happened to you?
波比, 我好害怕.
Bobby, l'm so afraid.
里欧想杀死我.
Leo tried to kill me.
他知道我们了.
He knows about us.
他把我抓到锯木厂,
He took me up to the mill,
然后把我绑起来
就开始点火.
and he tied me up
and started the fire.
波比,
Bobby,
他还威胁我说要杀死你.
he told me he was gonna kill you.
想得倒美.
Fat chance.
我再也不会让他伤害我们半点了.
l won't let him hurt us anymore.
你恢复的怎样了?
Are you all right?
医生说恢复的不错.
Doctors seem to think so.
知道吗, 雪莉,
医院其实是个很危险的地方.
You know, Shelly,
hospitals are dangerous places.
首先, 这里挤满了
一大堆的病人.
First of all, they're crawling
with sick people.
第二,
这里的伙食难吃得要命.
And second of all,
that food can kill you.
所以
如果你想快点出院,
So if you wanna
get out of here pronto,
那么你就得
让波比我来好好医治你.
you're gonna have to let Bobby
be your doctor.
先让我们来检查一下这里,
雪莉小姐.
So let's just have a look here,
Miss Shelly.
哦, 你看起来
气色相当不错嘛.
Oh, you seem to be
coming along splendidly.
深呼吸.
Deep breath.
我诊断
你马上就要康复了.
l'd say you're on your way
to a complete recovery.
你快走吧.
You better go.
你是我的女人.
You're my girl.
波比.
Bobby.
我爱你.
l love you.
我想我也爱你.
l guess l love you too.
是的, 我想我也爱你.
Yeah, l guess l love you too.
波比·布里格斯.
Bobby Briggs.
- 他在这儿干嘛?
- 他不像来看病.
- What's he doing here?
- He doesn't look sick.
杜鲁门警长, 没想到你也有
头脑灵活的时候,不赖嘛,
Sheriff Truman, to see this kind
of investigative genius at work,
难得啊.
it's just a real treat for me.
艾德.
Ed.
你没事吧?
我听说你受伤了
How are you doing?
l heard you stopped a couple.
我没事. 纳丁怎样了?
l'm okay. How's Nadine?
唉, 她现在昏迷中.
Well, she's in a coma.
医生说我现在只能等着.
希望她有求生的意志.
They say there's nothing we could do.
She has to wanna come back.
你能坚持住吗?
How are you holding up?
嗯, 也只能这样了,
Well, all l can do is sit here,
坐着干等
回忆着以前的事.
thinking about the things
l should have said or done.
艾德, 别太难过了.
Ed, don't be too hard on yourself.
我从来不相信命运,
库珀探员.
l never believed in fate,
Agent Cooper.
我总是觉得
l always felt
路是自己走出来的, 自己承担
责任, 管好自己的事.
you make your own way, you take care
of your own, you pick up after yourself.
呵,小农意识?
Farmer's AImanac?
艾伯特, 我想艾德
单独谈谈.
Albert, l would like
to speak to Ed.
艾伯特, 来,我请你喝咖啡吧.
Albert, l'll buy you a cup of coffee.
坐吧, 艾德.
Take a seat, Ed.
我真不敢相信.
l saw this coming.
它就在我眼前发生了.
l didn't wanna believe it.
最糟糕的是,我甚至怀疑自己
是否也在刻意的
What's worse is l'm sitting thinking
that maybe there's a part of me
让它发生.
that didn't wanna stop her.
这个念头快让我受不了.
And that's a full load.
艾德, 你是什么时候结婚的?
When did you get married, Ed?
高中刚毕业.
Right out of high school.
诺玛和我
在一起四年了.
Norma and l had been together
about four years.
当时大家都认定我们会结婚的.
本来是的.
Everybody figured we'd get hitched.
That'd be that.
那是我和纳丁根本就不是很熟.
l barely knew Nadine to say hello to.
那年春天, 就在一个倒霉的周末,
That spring, one bad weekend,
诺玛跟着汉克跑路了.
Norma ran off with Hank.
我的内心痛苦极了,
我糊涂了.
l was so twisted up inside,
l couldn't see straight.
当我睁开双眼的时候,
When l opened my eyes,
纳丁,
就睡在我身旁.
there was Nadine,
right in front of me.
那一刻似乎也很甜蜜迷人,
There was something so sweet,
她看起来是那么的无助.
so helpless about her.
我们兜了一晚上风.
We drove all night.
绕过蒙大拿州大瀑布后
在一个小镇上停了车,
Ended up in some little town
in Montana, out past Great Falls,
我向她求婚.
and l asked her to marry me.
半疯, 半醉, 半开玩笑的,
Half joking, half drunk, half crazy.
我们都以为结婚
会让我们的生活平静下来.
lt was light before we found
a justice of the peace.
但是,诺玛...
And Norma...
唔, 其实她根本
没和汉克睡过.
Well, she hadn't even
slept with Hank.
我看着她的脸
当她知道...
The look on her face
when she found out...
后来我和纳丁, 去了英格·帕斯
我爸爸留下来的一个小木屋里.
Nadine and l, we went up to my dad's
old cabin up in Eagle Pass.
度蜜月.
Honeymoon.
我但是还打算借散布的机会
向纳丁提出离婚,
l was hoping maybe we'd get around
to talking about a divorce,
或者, 先分居什么的.
annulment, something.
但是纳丁是那么的高兴.
But Nadine was so happy.
你明白吗, 唉呀,
And you know, by golly,
蜜月里
我打瞎了纳丁的眼睛.
l shot out Nadine's eye
on that honeymoon.
你说什么, 艾德?
What do you mean, Ed?
蜜月头一天,
我们去打野鸡.
The first day,
we were hunting pheasant.
纳丁是个神枪手
其实我们已经打到好几只野鸡了.
Nadine's a crack shot
and we already had a couple of birds.
但是我感觉很好,还想打.
And l felt good shooting.
听着枪声回荡在山谷,
又好像从山上滚下来.
Listening to the sound echoing,
roll down those hills.
于是我开火了.
l fired.
没想到一粒弹片在石头上反弹回来
把纳丁的眼睛打个正着.
A piece of buckshot skipped off a rock
and caught Nadine square in the eye.
嘿, 那一定疼死了.
Man, that's a tough one.
我们开车回镇
她就一直伏在我的膝盖上.
She laid across my lap
as we drove back to town.
她一点都没哭.
She never cried.
没怪罪过我半点.
She never blamed me.
更从来没有因此而恨过我.
She never hated me for it.
几个月后,
诺玛嫁给了汉克.
Couple of months later,
Norma married Hank.
所以我从来不相信命运.
自作孽, 活该.
So l don't believe in fate.
You make your bed, you sleep in it.
很难过听到这些.
Sorry.
艾德, 有人来看你了.
Ed, someone here to see you.
一个躺在微笑袋子里的男人.
A man in a smiling bag.
这边搞完了
就把詹姆斯送回局里去.
Take James right back to the station
when you're done here.
艾德真可怜.
Poor Ed.
纳丁也是.
Poor Nadine.
- 是啊.
- Yeah.
艾伯特, 你为什么
不趁现在
Albert, why don't you
take this opportunity
去大北方酒店
订个房呢.
to check in
at The Great Northern.
护士, 我不是开玩笑的,
你最好和厨房打个招呼,那些食物实在....
Nurse, l really mean it,
you better speak to that kitchen.
哈里, 艾伯特在大北方酒店
订完房以后,
Harry, when Albert finishes up
at The Great Northern,
我们在局里面碰头.
we'll meet back at the station.
我要开始布置整个计划了.
l'm ready to lay the whole thing out.
糖果和饮料呢?
Rocks and bottles?
粉笔和黑板
就行了.
Chalk and blackboard
will be just fine.
- 果冻加面包甜甜圈怎样?
- 哈里, 那还用说吗.
- Jelly doughnuts?
- Harry, that goes without saying.
那回见
顺便买些汤回来喝.
l'll come back later
and l'll bring some soup.
这里的伙食有够恶心的
比所有病毒都恶心.
The food in these places will kill you
quicker than most diseases.
我知道.
So l hear.
还有, 别忘了
给我带甜点.
Now, you know
l have a sweet tooth too.
我会给你带
巧克力花生牛油馅饼.
l've got
a chocolate-peanut butter pie.
诺玛, 别骗我哦.
Norma, l'm serious.
要一大个哦.
Bring the whole pie.
我给你带两大个,够没.
l'll bring you two.
够了.
Okay.
- 好好休息.
- 回见.
- Feel better, sweetie.
- Bye.
回见.
Bye.
儿子.
Son.
爸.
Dad.
你愿意...
Would you...
...过来一起坐吗?
...care to join me?
那好吧.
Okay.
今天在学校过的好吗?
How was school today?
学校?
School?
还好.
Fine.
很好.
That's good.
你呢，工作怎样?
How was work?
工作? 工作不错.
Work? Work was good.
- 爸?
- 是的, 儿子.
- Dad?
- Yes, son.
其实， 你的工作到底是干什么的?
What is it that you do, exactly?
机密.
That's classified.
波比, 你要
来一块馅饼吗?
Bobby, would you care
for a piece of pie?
今天的橘莓馅饼
特别可口.
The huckleberries are particularly
delicious today.
特别新鲜 特别美味.
Particularly fresh and delicious.
不了, 谢谢.
No, thanks.
波比,
Bobby,
愿意和我分享一些东西吗?
may l share something with you?
那好吧.
Okay.
我昨晚睡觉时做了个梦.
A vision l had in my sleep last night.
一个非一般的梦,
As distinguished from a dream,
一个由潜意识
对日常生活
which is mere sorting
and cataloging
进行分类
和重整后的梦.
of the day's events
by the subconscious.
那个梦境.
This was a vision.
清晰可见
犹如山涧清泉.
Fresh and clear
as a mountain stream.
它慢慢显示，越来越清晰.
The mind revealing itself to itself.
在梦里,
ln my vision,
我站在一间
宫殿的门前,
l was on the veranda
of a vast estate,
一座富丽堂皇
结构匀称的宫殿.
a palazzo
of some fantastic proportion.
宫殿的窗户透出
一簇微弱的灯光
There seemed to emanate from it
a light from within this
隐隐约约, 映射出那些漂亮的大理石.
gleaming, radiant marble.
我认得这个地方. 我来过, 事实上,
那里就是我出生的地方.
l'd known this place. l had, in fact,
been born and raised there.
是我人生的首次回归.
This was my first return.
回归到任最深处的生命之源.
A reunion with the deepest
well springs of my being.
我围着房子转悠, 我很高兴地注意到
Wandering about, l noticed happily
它一直都被
打理得非常整整有条.
that the house had been
immaculately maintained.
有一个小客房
在它的旁边,
There had been added a number
of additional rooms,
但是小客房丝毫不碍眼
完全和其他建筑物融为一体了,
but in a way that blended so seamlessly
with the original construction,
谁也不会察觉
它有什么不妥.
one would never detect
any difference.
回到房子里面的
大客厅,
Returning to the house's
grand foyer,
有人来敲门了.
there came a knock at the door.
是我的儿子.
My son was standing there.
他看起来多么快乐，无忧无虑的.
He was happy and carefree.
充满和谐和欣喜
前途无量的人生.
Clearly living a life
of deep harmony and joy.
我们拥抱在一起.
We embraced.
满怀温暖与爱,
一个最纯粹的拥抱.
A warm and loving embrace,
nothing withheld.
那一刻, 我们俩, 化为一体了.
We were, in this moment, one.
我醒来了，但那种奇妙的感觉
还久久徘徊在我心间
My vision ended and l awoke
with a tremendous feeling
让我感到你和你的未来
of optimism and confidence
多么乐观，自信.
in you and your future.
就这样，一个关于你的梦.
That was my vision of you.
真的吗?
Really?
我很高兴能有这个机会
和你分享这个梦.
l'm so glad to have had this opportunity
to share it with you.
我祝福你
一生顺风.
l wish you nothing
but the very best in all things.
谢谢你, 爸.
Thank you, Dad.
- 回见. 电联.
- 好的.
- See you later. Call.
- Okay.
少校?
Major?
觉得今天的馅饼怎样?
How was the pie?
一如既往地出色.
Exceptional, as always.
雪莉怎样了?
How is Shelly?
等一下再说吧.
l can't talk right now.
那好, 她喜欢那些的花吗?
Well, how did she like the flowers?
劳拉·帕尔默被害当晚，
她有两个约会.
The night Laura Palmer was killed, it
appears she made two appointments.
她的日记里写到,
好紧张今晚和「詹」的见面.
ln her diary she had written,
''Nervous about meeting J tonight.''
被提到的「詹」
应该就是詹姆斯·赫尔利.
l now believe this was a reference
to James Hurley.
她觉得紧张是因为
她打算告诉他
She was nervous
because she planned to tell him
要和他分手.
she didn't wanna see him anymore.
就在她准备溜出家门的时候,
她接到了一个电话.
Before she snuck out of the house,
she received a phone call.
她的第二个约会
里欧·强生
We believe it was Leo Johnson
making the second appointment
约在当晚深夜.
for sometime later that night.
劳拉见到詹姆斯后,
一直和他待到12:30,
Laura met James,
was with him until 1 2:30,
然后, 她独自去到史巴克伍和21区
十字路口,
when, at the intersection
of Sparkwood and 21 ,
她上了摩托车
开进了树林里.
she jumped from the bike
and ran into the woods.
我们相信她是去那里
见雅克·雷诺,
We believe she met up there
with Jacques Renault,
里欧·强生和朗尼特·珀拉斯奇.
Leo Johnson and Ronette Pulaski.
他们一起, 开车拐到了一条小路上
这条小路通往雷诺的小木屋.
Together, they drove to the foot
of the trail leading to Jacques's cabin.
他们翻过小路的时候,
给灵木女士听到.
They climbed the trail, they were heard
passing by the cabin of the Log Lady.
他们大约在凌晨1点钟
到了雅克·雷诺的小木屋.
They reached Jacques Renault's cabin
at approximately 1 a.m.
然后开始喝酒，嗑药，狂欢.
劳拉被绑了起来
Drugs and alcohol were consumed.
Laura was tied up
和里欧，雅克两个
同时发生性关系.
and had sexual relations
with both Leo and Jacques.
那只鹦鹉沃尔多从笼子里跑了出来
啄伤了劳拉.
Waldo the bird was let out of his cage
and attacked Laura.
之后里欧和雅克打了起来.
雅克逃到屋外晕倒了.
Leo and Jacques fought.
Jacques went outside and passed out.
当他醒过来后,
里欧和女生们都已经走了.
When he came to,
Leo and the girls were gone.
我们相信里欧是一个人
徒步顺着小路离开的,
We believe Leo hiked back down
the trail to his Corvette alone,
把女生们都甩下.
leaving the girls behind.
现在可以确定,
现场还有一个神秘人.
The reason being,
there was a third man.
豪克副警长发现的证据表明
确实还有一个我们未知的神秘人在场
Deputy Hawk found evidence
of a third man
在雅克的小木屋
窗外.
outside the window
of Jacques's cabin.
神秘人掳走了劳拉和朗尼特
把他们掳到铁路那里，然后绑起来.
The third man took Laura and Ronette
to the train where they were tied up.
劳拉是第二次被绑,
朗尼特则是第一次.
Laura for the second time,
Ronette for the first.
凶手用钝器,
袭击朗尼特
Using a blunt object,
the killer hit Ronette
把她砸至昏迷.
and knocked her unconscious.
他当时一定是急于
要将劳拉置于死地,
He must have been so intent
on killing Laura,
所以没有意识到朗尼特
恢复知觉并逃脱了.
he didn't realize that Ronette
regained consciousness and escaped.
也有可能是
他根本不在意.
Either he didn't know
or he didn't care.
他堆砌了一个土堆
He made a small mound of dirt
把劳拉的半心项链
放在上面.
and put the half-heart necklace
of Laura's on top.
然后他把一个印有「R」字的小纸片
塞进她无名指的指甲缝里.
He then placed a small cut out letter R
under the nail of her left ring finger.
另一个受害人特里萨·班克斯的指甲缝里
也塞有一张印有「T」字的小纸片.
You'll recall that he placed the letter T
under the fingernail of Teresa Banks.
他留下了一封血书,
"与火同行."
He left a note written in blood,
''Fire walk with me.''
值得注意的是.
Here's the interesting thing.
经过化验.
血书上的血型不是里欧的,
The blood on the note was tested.
lt doesn't match Leo's,
也不是雅克，劳拉或者朗尼特的.
Jacques's, Laura's or Ronette's.
我们推测
血型是属于神秘人的.
So we surmise the killer wrote the note
in his own blood.
是稀有血型, 负AB型.
lt's a rare type, AB negative.
豪克副警长发现了一条毛巾
被丢在了小路上
The towel that Deputy Hawk found
five miles down the tracks
上面也染满了负AB型的血.
was soaked in blood of that type.
豪克还发现, 在毛巾的附近,
有一些褪了色的小碎纸片.
He also found, near the towel,
scraps of faded paper.
这些小碎纸片可能
是凶手遗留下来的.
These scraps may have been left
by the killer.
我们会把它们送回
华盛顿作检测.
They'll be sent back
to Washington D.C. for testing.
我明白, 安迪.
我了解, 我了解, 我了解.
l know, Andy.
l know, l know, l know.
这就是一宗我们常常所说的
实时连环命案.
lt's what we call
a real three-hankie crime.
艾伯特·罗生佛洛尔,
Albert Rozerfeld,
我真的非常讨厌你那自以为是的态度
对杜鲁门警长是这样，对每个人都是这样.
l don't like the way you talk smart
about Sheriff Truman or anybody.
快给我闭上你的臭嘴吧!
You just shut your mouth!
劳拉·帕尔默死了.
Laura Palmer is dead.
雅克·雷诺死了.
Jacques Renault is dead.
朗尼特·珀拉斯奇和里欧·强生
正昏迷中.
Ronette Pulaski and Leo Johnson
are in comas.
鹦鹉沃尔多也死了.
Waldo the bird is dead.
现在只剩下神秘人了.
This leaves only the third man.
- 你要关门吗?
- 要关, 要关. 不然会很冷的.
- You want this door closed?
- Yeah, yeah. We'll frost our rooms.
- 谢谢你送我一程, 哈里.
- 没事.
- l sure do appreciate the ride, Harry.
- No problem.
我路上也好
有个伴陪陪, 皮特.
l always appreciate
your company, Pete.
年轻人, 这些浓烟
差点要了我的小命.
Boy, this smoke inhalation
is nasty business.
就像把我的嘴套在了
大巴士的排气管上一样.
l feel like somebody taped my lips
to the tailpipe of a bus.
放松点，没事的.
Take her easy.
- 那乔西去哪儿了?
- 哦, 嗯, 这里可能有留言.
- So where the hell is Josie?
- Oh, well, maybe this will tell us.
"亲爱的皮特,
''Dear Pete,
我出镇一段时间
l had to leave the town
西雅图有点急事
需要我去处理一下.
on an emergency
of business to Seattle.
我到了给你电话.
l will phone you when l arrive.
祝你在锯木厂
过的愉快.
Hope you did a good day
at the mill.
冰箱里有姜啤酒.
爱你的, 乔西." 就这些了.
There is ginger beer in the refrig.
Love, Josie.'' There you go.
- 上面留了电话号码吗?
- 没有.
- ls there a phone number in there?
- No.
- 她有说具体在西雅图那里吗?
- 没有, 没有, 只说了去西雅图
- Does she say where she's staying?
- No, no, she goes off to Seattle
约莫三个月她就会去一次.
once every three months or so.
我说啊, 她去那里是为了
实施一项罪恶的秘密活动.
You want my opinion, l think she goes
over there to indulge a secret vice.
- 那是什么?
- 疯狂购物啊.
- What's that?
- Shopping.
每次都是那样
几乎把半个百货商店都搬回来.
Comes back
with half a department store.
皮特,
Pete,
我们还没找到凯萨琳.
we haven't found Catherine.
知道.
Yeah.
我估计.
l figured.
当然希望是好消息,
l know you wanna hope for the best,
但也要做好最坏的打算.
but you ought to prepare for the worst.
噢, 亲爱的.
Oh, dear.
我一直在想
谁会先离开人世.
l always figured
l'd be the one to go first.
我意思是, 退一步想象
l mean, if you was laying odds
如果在核战中
只死剩下一个人的话,
on the last person standing
after an atomic war,
那肯定是她.
l'd have bet on her.
是啊, 她以前真的是生龙活虎, 好.
Yeah, she was a tiger, all right.
说白了吧, 她就是只母老虎
和她一起生活简直是与虎同行.
No use mincing words,
she was plain hell to live with.
令人望而生畏.
Plain hell.
但...
But...
...毕竟, 我们也曾有过
一段美好的时光.
...once, there was a little bit
of heaven there too.
哦, 是的，我们的确有过.
Oh, l'm sure there was.
啊, 上帝.
Oh, God.
我只希望
时间会慢慢地冲淡痛苦.
This will take a little while
to sink in, l suppose.
我想会的.
l suppose it will.
上帝会超度那些悲惨痛苦的灵魂.
God help her miserable soul.
我是爱她的.
l loved her.
蓝松小舍.
Blue Pine Lodge.
请乔西·帕卡德,
听电话?
Could l speak to Josie Packard,
please?
- 哦, 她不在.
- 那她什么时候回来?
- WeII, she's not here right now.
- Can you tell me when she'll be back?
唔, 她出镇去了.
你是谁啊?
Well, she's out of town.
Who's calling?
请帮我接
国际长途.
l'd like to place
an international call, please.
是的，香港.
Collect to Hong Kong.
它听起来不像...?
Doesn't that sound...?
我是说, 我吃了,
虽然我也不太清楚那个是什么咚咚.
l mean, l ate it,
but l didn't really know what it was.
我在法国美食杂志上见过,
l read about it in this French magazine,
他们把那东西的整个头浸泡
一种类似牛奶布丁的东西里面.
and they take the entire head and dip it
in a kind of blancmange pudding.
然后沾上小麦粉
填满核桃和热糖浆
And then they roll it in oats and stuff it
full of walnuts and hot rocks
- 还有香味曲奇.
- 荷恩先生, 荷恩先生.
- and a spice cookie.
- Mr. Horne, Mr. Horne.
- 最后把馅料都塞进大耳朵狗里.
- 荷恩先生, 荷恩先生.
- They wrap it in papiIIon.
- Mr. Horne, Mr. Horne.
再用糖衣
把它封起来
They seal the edges
with a sugar glaze
- 放在烤箱里烤.
- 荷恩先生, 荷恩先生.
- and bake it under glass.
- Mr. Horne, Mr. Horne.
不可思议.
That sounds incredible.
好吃的想死.
lt is to die for.
你今天见过欧蕊没有?
Have you seen Audrey today?
没有, 没见过.
No, l haven't.
汉克·詹宁斯.
Hank Jennings.
杰利和班杰民,荷恩兄弟.
Jerry and Benjamin Horne.
乔西去哪儿了?
Where's Josie?
她昨天晚上走了.
She left last night.
预先安排好的?
Prearranged?
她不想和这次纵火
扯上关系.
She wanted to put a little distance
between her and the smell of smoke.
这个女人果然有心计.
Sound strategy.
那里欧·强生呢.
Next business, Leo Johnson.
他现在昏迷中.
He's in a coma.
脑损伤,废了.
Looks like brain damage.
里欧一天还活着, 就有把柄在他们手上?
With Leo, how could they tell?
你为什么没把他彻底干掉?
Why isn't he dead?
我已经用口径44的手枪正中了他心脏.
l caught him center shot with a .44.
我不想冒然跑进他房子里.
Couldn't risk going inside.
而且附近已经烧起来了.
我必须要避开巡逻警车.
Neighborhood was hot.
l had to sneak past patrols as it was.
有人看到你吗?
Anybody see you?
没有.
Negative.
里欧当时在屋里劈柴.
He was chopping wood.
劈柴? 在屋里?
Chopping wood? lnside?
- 是, 你又不是不了解他.
- 等等.
- Yeah, you know Leo.
- Wait a minute.
- 在屋里劈柴?
- 是.
- Chopping wood inside?
- Yeah.
你知道他这人啦.
You know Leo.
好了. 还有什么?
All right. What's next?
凯萨琳.
Catherine.
死了吗?
Dead?
我故意打了电话叫她到烘干室
那时候那里已经烧起来了.
My phone call put her in the drying
shed when the place went up.
应该把她烧的
一点没剩了.
Sounds like buried
with the wreckage.
那样高温的烧法,
那帮警察能找到牙齿就算走狗运了.
Heat like that,
they'll be lucky to find teeth.
她的牙齿曾经是那么的漂亮.
And they were such pretty teeth.
干的不错.
Marvelous.
太精彩了.
先生们,
Gentlemen,
如果那帮条子这样都不检控
死鬼凯萨琳和她姘头里欧
if they don't hang the arson
on the late lamented Catherine
纵火罪的话,
and her co-conspirator Leo,
我就挥刀自宫.
l'll give up sex.
这回赢定了.
That's confidence.
那我们现在怎么分账?
What do we do with the ledger?
汉克,
Hank,
你的问题对荷恩兄弟来说
实在太有创造性了.
you leave the creative thinking
to the brothers Horne.
你这块二头肌.
我们教你干嘛你就该干嘛.
You're a bicep.
Relax until we say, ''Flex.''
现在, 还没轮到你发飙.
Now, that really makes me mad.
你们这些家伙.
You guys.
进来.
Come in.
为什么把我关起来?
Why is the door to my room locked?
是谁允许你这样做的?
And who's the refrigerator?
老板对你昨晚的表现
很不满意.
The owner was a little disappointed
in your performance last night.
哦, 老板又不是我喜欢的那种型.
Well, the owner isn't exactly my type.
哦? 那什么型是你喜欢的呀?
And what is your type exactly?
反正不是你. 开玩笑的.
Not you. No offense.
嘿.
Hey.
你给我放明白点
小公主.
Let's get one thing straight
between us, princess.
好.
Okay.
我不想再听到任何
有关你的投诉.
l don't wanna hear another complaint
about you.
在我这儿干活,
When you work for me,
什么客你都得接.
everybody's your type.
诺玛?
Norma?
嗨, 我是唐娜.
Hi, it's Donna.
我想问一下关于「上门送餐服务」的事.
l'm calling about Meals on Wheels.
我想以后换我替劳拉去上门送餐
你觉得行吗.
l'm gonna take over Laura's route
if that's okay with you.
那好吧.
Okay.
太好了.
Great.
还有, 我可以用双食店
的车去送餐吗?
Listen, can l use the Double R
station wagon?
没问题.
All right.
太好了.
Great.
那明天9点见.
Then l'll see you tomorrow at 9.
格斯登将要为大家
预报今晚的表演节目.
Gersten's gonna tell us
about tonight's proceedings.
她还有一些好消息要告诉大家.
我们为她感到荣幸.
She has some very good news.
We're all very proud of her.
晚上好 .
Good evening.
我是格斯登·海沃德
欢迎大家
l'm Gersten Hayward
and l'd like to welcome you all
光临海沃德家夜总会.
to the Hayward Supper Club.
今晚
我将为大家表演
l'm going to be playing
various selections
丰富多彩的音乐节目.
of music for you this evening.
好消息就是
我已经入选
My good news is
that l was chosen
校园剧女主角
精灵公主.
to be the fairy princess
in my school play.
这是我订做的演出服.
This is my special dress.
还有, 我这次期中考
数学和英语
Also, l got the highest scores
in mathematics and English
都得了最高分.
this mid-season term.
跟我的姐姐们哈里特和唐娜
以前读书的时候一样.
Just as my sisters Harriet
and Donna did before me.
所以我再也不用担心
让家族的光辉历史蒙羞了.
So now l don't have to worry
about being ashamed anymore.
在我表演之前,
哈里特首先为大家念一首诗
Before l play,
Harriet would like to read a poem
一首关于你的女儿
我们的好友劳拉的诗.
about your daughter
and our friend Laura.
劳拉
It was Laura
我看见她红光焕发
And I saw her gIowing
在黑暗的树林里
In the dark woods
她微微的笑着
I saw her smiIing
我们都哭了
We were crying and I saw her
而她却笑了
Laughing
她在我们的悲伤中
翩翩起舞
In our sadness
I saw her dancing
并永恒的活在了我们的梦中
It was Laura Iiving in my dreams
那就是劳拉
It was Laura
生命的赤热光辉
The gIow was Iife
她微笑着对我们说
Her smiIe was to say
哭吧
It was aII right to cry
树精灵也在为我们悲泣
The woods was our sadness
她飞舞的身影呼唤着我们
The dance was her caIIing
那就是劳拉
It was Laura
她就这样和我轻轻的吻别了
And she came to kiss me goodbye
真实美极了. 谢谢你.
That was wonderful. Thank you.
格斯登.
Gersten.
现在我要表演的门德尔松的
"回旋随想曲, 作品号14."
Now l'm going to play Mendelssohn's
''Rondo Capriccioso, Opus 1 4.''
「上门送餐服务」的名单和地图
我已经搞到手了.
l got the list and map
for Meals on Wheels.
我明天就去.
l'm going to start tomorrow.
牛逼.
Aces.
漫漫长日, 难熬吧?
Long day, Will?
感觉就像坐在那儿听
一部老掉牙的冗长歌剧.
l feel like l've sat through
back-to-back operas.
在医学院读书时, 我们就学会了
一天只睡几个小时或者只打个盹.
ln med school, we learned to live
on three hours a night and cat naps.
锯木厂发生的事实在太可怕了.
lt's terrible about the mill.
是啊. 报道说
将近150人因此而失业.
Yeah. They say more
than 1 50 jobs may be lost.
太吓人了. 真实太吓人了.
Awful. Just awful.
但有人欢喜有人愁啊
l suppose this will open the door
对本·荷恩的发展大计来说
就是天大的喜讯.
for Ben Horne
and his big development plans.
嗯, 我同时是你和他两个人的律师,
Well, as his lawyer, and yours,
对此我还是不做评论的好.
of course l can't comment.
那好, 同时我也是你的医生, 利兰,
Well, as your doctor, Leland,
你的白头发到底是怎么搞的?
what the hell happened to your hair?
很奇怪, 是吧?
lt is strange, isn't it?
唔, 我只是...
Well, l just...
我一觉醒来,
在镜子里就发现自己这样了.
l woke up this morning,
looked in the mirror and there it was.
真是一夜白了少年头啊
lt had literally changed overnight.
嗯, 仔细想想
你最近经历的事也够...
Well, considering
all you've been through...
你知道吗, 有趣的是,
You know, the funny thing about it is,
看看, 我已经意识到无论如何
seeing it, l realized that l had
要坚强起来，靠自己熬过去.
turned a corner somehow.
是的，尽管我现在
还是如此沉痛,
l feel a great deal
of sadness still, yes,
但我不能任由它把我压垮.
but it wasn't as overwhelming to me.
我必须要除掉
这块心头大石.
l physically felt as if a great weight
had been lifted from my heart.
- 希望是吧.
- Perhaps it has.
希望你能熬过去.
Perhaps it has.
天啊, 我要放声高歌.
God, l feel like singing.
会让我心情好起来.
That would be very nice.
不, 我真的要放声高歌.
No, l really feel like singing a song.
- 利兰?
- 来吧, 各位. 大家都高兴起来.
- Leland?
- Come on, everybody. Get happy.
- "高兴起来."
- "高兴起来"?
- ''Get Happy.''
- ''Get Happy''?
忘却你的烦恼
高兴起来
Forget your troubIes
And just get happy
把你的忧虑收拾起来扔掉
You gotta pack aII your cares away
高唱「哈利路亚」
来吧, 高兴起来
Sing haIIeIujah
Come on, get happy
为世界末日做好准备
Get ready for the judgment day
阳光依然灿烂
高唱「哈利路亚」
The sun is shinin'
Come on, get happy
上帝在向你招手
The Lord is waitin' to take your hand
高唱「哈利路亚」
来吧, 让我们高兴起来
Sing haIIeIujah
Come on, get happy
我们将奔向乐土
We're going to that promised Iand
我们淌过河水
在潮汐中洗净你罪恶
We're headin' cross the river
Wash your sins away in the tide
噢哦，宁静满布在世界的另一端
It's, oh, so peacefuI on the other side
忘却你的烦恼吧
来吧, 让我们高兴起来
Forget your troubIes
Come on, get happy
快把内心的忧伤赶的远远的
You better chase aII your cares away
高唱「哈利路亚」
来吧, 让我们高兴起来
Sing haIIeIujah
Come on, get happy
为世界末日做好准备
Get ready for the judgment day
高唱「哈利路亚」
来吧, 让我们高兴起来
Sing haIIeIujah
Come on, get happy
高唱「哈利路亚」
来吧, 让我们高兴起来
Sing haIIeIujah
Come on, get happy
为世界末日做好准备
Get ready for the judgment day
高唱「哈利路亚」
来吧, 让我们高兴起来
Sing haIIeIujah
Come on, get happy
为世界末日...--
Get ready for the judgment d--
唐娜, 快拿急救包.
Donna, get my bag.
利兰?
Leland?
- 爸, 他怎样了?
- 还好，没什么大碍.
- Dad, is he okay?
- l'm sure it's nothing serious.
哦, 上帝啊.
Oh, God.
我好高兴.
l feel happy.
来，我们开始跳比津舞吧.
''Begin the Beguine.''
黛安, 现在晚上11:55了,
Diane, it's 1 1 :55 p.m.,
我中枪后已经
持续工作19个小时了
approximately 1 9 hours
since the shooting incident
我几乎萌生了
要归隐田园
which nearly caused me
to make a premature purchase
的念头.
of the proverbial farm.
我现在累得像狗一样.
l'm dog-tired.
原来一个人
可以极限到这种程度.
A man can only go so long
without submitting to a period of rest.
按照美军
For as we know from experiments
在朝鲜战争时
的经验教训,
conducted on American Gls
during the Korean War,
睡眠权利被剥夺后
绝对会导致间歇性精神病.
sleep deprivation is a one-way ticket
to temporary psychosis.
我觉得自己已经成了工作狂了.
And l'm working on a three-day jag.
你知道我昨晚多傻吗, 黛安,
l got so goofy last night, Diane,
我躺在地上时开始在想
我是想死呢，还是想活呢,
lying here wondering
whether l was going to live or die,
然后我看见了
一个巨人出现在我房间里.
that l thought l saw
a giant in my room.
啊，这个事
还是下次再说吧.
Or perhaps that's a story
l'll save for another time.
我是, 戴尔,
This is me, Dale,
大北方酒店315房,
完毕.
room 31 5 at The Great Northern Hotel,
signing off.
特派探员.
Special agent.
特派探员. 特派探员.
Special agent. Special agent.
特派探员, 你听到吗?
Special agent, are you there?
我给你留了言.
你收到我留的纸条了吗?
l left you a note.
Didn't you get my note?
我把它从门缝里塞进去了.
保佑你一定要看到它.
l slipped it under your door.
You must have seen it.
嗯, 我在这儿呢
单眼杰克赌场.
Well, l'm up here
at One-Eyed Jack's.
说真的,
我想我这次搞的有点过火了.
To be perfectly honest,
l think l'm in a little over my head.
已经超过了我的能力范围.
Not that l can't handle it.
我是说, 其实我只想帮你
破案,
l mean, if l'm gonna help you out
with your investigations,
但是现在的情形
比我原来想象的要危险的多
l'm sure l'll be put into situations
a lot more dangerous than this
不是我所能控制的了.
on a fairly regular basis.
但是...
But it's just...
...你要明白, 尽管这是我头一次出远门.
...you know, my first time out.
但我也事先作了一些准备的.
l could use a little expert guidance.
所以，你知道我已经查到什么了,
荷恩百货大厦
So you know,
there is a connection
和单眼杰克赌场
原来都是一伙的.
between Horne's Department Store
and One-Eyed Jack's.
是我爸爸, 两个地方都是属于他的.
lt's my father, he owns the place.
那个胆小鬼马屁精经理巴蒂斯
负责从香水柜台
Little ball of sleaze named Battis
helps to recruit some of the girls
招募新的女孩子.
from the perfume counter.
明天我会再去查查看
劳拉和朗尼特是不是也给招进来过.
Tomorrow l'm gonna try to find out
if Laura and Ronette came up here.
我只希望你不会觉得
我为你做的这些事微不足道.
l hope you won't think any less of me
for trying to help you.
你明白吗, 我只为了你
才会做这些事的.
You know, l promise l only did it
with the best of intentions.
所以，如果...
And if there's any way...
如果现在你在世界的某处
听见了我的求救声,
lf there's any way in the world
that you can hear me right now,
就请快来救救我吧.
please help me.
救我. 救我.
Help me. Help me.
抱歉把你吵醒了.
Sorry to wake you.
我不是做梦吧.
l am not dreaming.
有件事我忘记告诉你了.
l forgot to tell you something.
那个微笑的袋子
你的暗示中了.
You were right
about the smiling bag.
我给你的暗示
不会错的.
The things l tell you
will not be wrong.
好了，现在听我说.
Better to listen than to talk.
我相信你.
l believe you.
不要急于
一次得到所有的答案.
Don't search
for all the answers at once.
万事有道，一切都安排好了
只需一步一脚印的走下去.
A path is formed
by laying one stone at a time.
有一个人看见了神秘人.
One person saw the third man.
见过3次, 是的,
Three have seen him, yes,
不仅仅是他的肉身.
but not his body.
一个你认识的人.
One only known to you.
他已经准备好了，就等你去问.
Ready now to talk.
还有一件事.
One more thing.
你忘东西了.
You forgot something.
啊?
What?
Laura! Laura!
Laura!